A Guide to the Records of Julian A. Burruss, President, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1906-1946
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Records of Julian A. Burruss, President, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1906-1946
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 2/8
72.0 cu. ft. 52 boxes, 1 oversize folder
The bulk of the collection contains correspondence concerning Julian Ashby Burruss' tenure as president of Virginia Polytechnic Institute, but also includes lecture notes, reports to the Board of Trustees of the State Normal School, and Experiment Station reports.
Burruss, Julian Ashby, 1876-1947
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Julian Ashby Burruss Papers were donated to Special Collections.
Biographical Note
Julian Ashby Burruss was born in Richmond, Virginia in 1876. He was the first alumnus-President, having graduated with honors in civil engineering from VPI in 1898. A hallmark of his long tenure in the presidency was a major administrative reorganization, which included: abolishing four deanships; broadening the scope and authority of the Deans of Agriculture and Engineering; establishing post of Dean of the College; abolishing College surgeon office and hiring full-time health officer; establishing office of business manager; placing directors of Agriculture Experiment Station and Extension Services under Dean of Agriculture; abolishing Registrar office; and placing athletic activities directly under control of college authorities.
Other highlights of Burruss' administration included: establishment of Engineering Experiment Station, 1921, and Engineering Extension Division, 1923; admittance of women to all departments, except military, 1921; founding of Future Farmers of Virginia, which became Future Farmers of America; first Ph.D. awarded; Radford State Teachers College merged with VPI and became Radford College, the Women's Division of VPI.
When mounting pressures and advancing age began to take a toll on Burruss, the Board of Visitors granted him a six-month leave of absence on 4 January 1945, and named John Hutcheson, Director of the Agriculture Extension Service, as Executive Assistant to the President. On 10 January 1945, Burruss suffered a fractured vertebrae in an automobile accident, so on 12 January, the Rector of the Board requested that Hutcheson assume the duties of the presidency immediately. At the Board meeting on 15 May, Burruss was elected "President Emeritus" and the search for a new president began.
Scope and Content
The Burruss collection contains mostly correspondence, including Board of Visitors correspondence (1919-1928). Some of the material in this collection pre-dates the beginning of Burruss' presidency and correspondence with faculty (1919-1946).
Also included in the collection are: lecture notes and writings (1906-1922, 1930-1931); reports to Board of Trustees of the State Normal School for Women at Harrisonburg (1908-1919); Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station financial reports (1910-1921); minutes of Normal School Board (1915-1917); payrolls (1918-1921); applications for faculty positions (1920-22); budget materials (1920-1924, 1926/27-1928/29, 1941-1942); reports of various committees (1921-25); invoices and insurance policies (1923-1924); contracts (1925-1946); departmental reports (1928); library annual reports (1935/36-1939/37); academic reports (1935-1940); Virginia Academy of Science Planning Committee material (1940); items relating to the Radford-VPI merger (1943-1944); reports of Treasurer to Department of Interior and Agriculture on income from fund derived for Land Grant Act of 1862 or from land grants made in lieu of 1862 grant; Public Works Administration records relating to buildings constructed on campus using PWA funds.
In addition to titles, some folders in the Contents List below include information about topics covered in the folder. Please note, these are highlights and not exhaustive lists of subjects contained in the file.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically into series an
Index Terms
Persons:
Burruss, Julian Ashby, 1876-1947
Corporate Names:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Office of the President.
Subjects:
Faculty; University Archives; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute
Contents List
- Series 1: Personal Correspondence and Papers, 1906-1945
  - Miscellaneous A-P (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Miscellaneous B-P (Box-folder 1-2)
  - J.A. Burruss's Educational Records (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Miscellaneous C-P (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Miscellaneous D-P (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Day Book (Planner), 1941 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Miscellaneous - E (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Miscellaneous F-P (Box-folder 1-8)
  - A. M. Frasier G-P (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Miscellaneous G-P (Box-folder 1-10)
  - Miscellaneous H-P (Box-folder 1-11)
  - Miscellaneous I-P (Box-folder 1-12)
  - Miscellaneous J-P (Box-folder 1-13)
  - Miscellaneous K-P (Box-folder 1-14)
  - Miscellaneous L-P (Box-folder 1-15)
  - Lawrence Manning - Class of '98 (Box-folder 1-17)
  - Lecture Notes & Writings, 1906-1922, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 1-18 and 1-18A)
  - Mary Baldwin College, Part 1, 1926-1945 (Box-folder 1-19)
  - Mary Baldwin College, Part 2, 1926-1945 (Box-folder 1-20)
  - Mary Baldwin College, Part 3, 1926-1945 (Box-folder 1-21)
  - Mary Baldwin College, Part 4, 1926-1945 (Box-folder 1-22)
  - Mary Baldwin College, Part 5, 1926-1945 (Box-folder 1-23)
  - Medical Commission 13-P (Box-folder 1-24)
  - Miller School 13-P (Box-folder 1-25)
  - Miscellaneous M-P (Box-folder 1-25A)
  - Miscellaneous N-P (Box-folder 1-26)
  - Miscellaneous O-P (Box-folder 1-27)
  - Miscellaneous P-P (Box-folder 1-28)
  - Miscellaneous Q-P (Box-folder 1-29)
  - Miscellaneous R-P (Box-folder 1-30)
  - Rotarily Yours (Box-folder 1-31)
  - Rotary, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 1-33)
  - Rotary, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 1-34)
  - Rotary, 1934 (Box-folder 1-35)
  - Rotary, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 1-36)
  - 55A Rural Education 18-P (Box-folder 1-37)
  - Miscellaneous S-P (Box-folder 1-38)
  - State Normal School for Women, Harrisonburg: Reports to Trustees, 1908-1919 (Box-folder 1-39)
  - State Normal School for Women: Minutes of the Board, 1915-1919 (Box-folder 53-39A)
  - State Normal School for Women: Correspondence as President, 1913-1919 (Box-folder 1-40)
  - Study in Business Admin., 1921 (Box-folder 2-41)
  - Miscellaneous T-P (Box-folder 2-42)
  - Talks, Including Radio (Box-folder 2-43)
  - Miscellaneous U-P (Box-folder 2-44)
  - Miscellaneous V-P (Box-folder 2-45)
  - Miscellaneous W-P (Box-folder 2-46)
  - Miscellaneous X-Y-Z (Box-folder 2-47)
  - Correspondence - Special Personal, 1921-1927 (Box-folder 2-48 and 2-48A)
    - Letter signed by Cyrus H. McCormick addressed to Burruss re: he cannot financially support an Ag. Eng. Bldg.
    - Senator Byrd denounces attack upon his character - pamphlet and letters
    - Blue Print of proposed organization of VPI, 1920-1921 by function
    - Blue Print (organization of VPI), 1919-1920
    - State politics included in this file
    - Declares Airport Acres an historic district made for Arsenal workers. Gives historical definition and identity (built by Pandappas)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1928-Mar. 1929 (Box-folder 2-49)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 2-50)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 2-51)
  - Correspondence - Personal, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 2-52)
- Series 2: Board of Visitors, 1919-1935
  - Board of Visitors (Misc. Blanket Letters, etc.), 1920-1928 (Box-folder 2-53)
    - Hazing and dismissal of 2 cadets 1923
    - Davidson Hall dedication (letter)
  - Board of Visitors Meeting, 1923-35 (Box-folder 2-53A)
  - Report to Board of Visitors from President (Box-folder 2-54)
    - Health Issues, Coal, Water, Sanitation, Sewers
  - Allen T. Eskeridge, 1924-28 (Box-folder 2-55)
  - J.F. Ferneyhough (Box-folder 2-56)
  - Hart-Lancaster, etc./Noell Fund Matters, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 2-57)
  - Harris Hart, 1919-1922 (Box-folder 2-58)
  - Harris Hart, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 2-59)
  - R.S. Horsley, 1928 (Box-folder 2-60)
  - J.M. Lewis, 1922-1928 (Box-folder 2-61)
  - R.S. Moss, 1919-1927 (Box-folder 2-62)
  - Robert A. Russell, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 2-63)
  - W. W. Spraul, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 2-64)
  - Chas. I. Wade, 1919-1923 (Box-folder 2-65)
  - Charles I. Wade, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 2-66)
  - F.S. Walker, 1920-1929 (Box-folder 2-67)
  - T. Gilbert Wood, 1922-1927 (Box-folder 2-69)
  - James P. Woods, 1924 (Box-folder 2-70)
  - T. Judson Wright, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 2-71)
- Series 3: Correspondence
  - Subseries 1: Faculty Correspondence, 1919-1920
    - Eliza Akers, 1920 (Box-folder 2-72)
    - B - Miscellaneous, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 2-73)
    - W.E. Barlow, 1920 (Box-folder 2-74)
    - R.B.H. Begg, 1920 (Box-folder 2-75)
    - G.B. Bright (Box-folder 2-76)
    - W. M. Brodie (Box-folder 2-77)
    - W.A. Brumfield, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 2-78)
    - O.C. Burkhart (Box-folder 2-79)
    - Miscellaneous - C (Box-folder 2-80)
      - College Water Supply
      - VT coal mine and conditions
    - Dean Campbell, Acting Executive, July 1919 (Box-folder 2-81)
    - Theo P. Campbell, Dean, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 2-82)
    - Dean Campbell, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-83A and 3-83B)
    - Col. C.C. Carson (Box-folder 3-84)
    - F.B. Carver, 1920 (Box-folder 3-85)
    - W.G. Chrisman (Box-folder 3-86)
    - W.G. Conner, 1920 (Box-folder 3-87)
    - J.J. Davis (Box-folder 3-88)
    - A.W. Drinkard, 1920 (Box-folder 3-89)
    - James Duff, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-90)
    - Thas. D. Eason (Box-folder 3-91)
    - James Eheart, 1920 (Box-folder 3-92)
    - W.B. Ellett, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-93)
    - W.T. Ellis (Box-folder 3-94)
    - Experiment Station, Letters Referred, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-95)
    - Extension Division, Letters Referred, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-96)
    - Faculty Matters, 1920 (Box-folder 3-97)
    - Faculty Relations Daylight Law, 1920 (Box-folder 3-98)
    - Faculty Miscellaneous Letters, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-99)
      - Coal situation - increase in prices at College mine
    - F.D. Fromme, 1920 (Box-folder 3-100)
    - Miscellaneous - G (Box-folder 3-101)
    - J.C. Glassett, Sec. To Mr. Burruss (Box-folder 3-102)
    - Jean C. Glassett (Box-folder 3-103)
    - Harry Gudheim (Box-folder 3-104)
    - Miscellaneous - H (Box-folder 3-105)
    - Anna G. Hannas, 1920 (Box-folder 3-106)
    - M.C. Harrison (Box-folder 3-107)
    - Dr. W.F. Henderson, 1920 (Box-folder 3-108)
    - H.H. Hill, 1920 (Box-folder 3-109)
    - C.W. Holdaway (Box-folder 3-110.)
    - Ray J. Holden (Box-folder 3-111)
    - R.E. Hunt, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-112)
    - J.R. Hutcheson, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-113)
    - T.B. Hutcheson, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-114)
    - Miscellaneous - J (Box-folder 3-115)
    - J.M. Johnson (Box-folder 3-116)
    - J.S.A. Johnson, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-117)
    - Theodore W. Knote (Box-folder 3-118)
    - Miscellaneous - L (Box-folder 3-119)
    - Dabney S. Lancaster, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-120)
    - Dabney, S. Lancaster (Box-folder 3-121)
    - Claudius Lee, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-122)
    - Claudius Lee, 1921 (Box-folder 3-123)
    - J.B. McBryde, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-124)
    - J.B. McBryde, 1921 (Box-folder 3-125)
    - A.B. Massey, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-126)
    - A.B. Massey, 1921 (Box-folder 3-127)
    - C.P. Miles, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-128)
    - C.P. Miles, 1921 (Box-folder 3-129)
    - Silas R. Minter (Box-folder 3-130)
    - C. M. Newman, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 3-131)
    - J. S. Nichols, 1920 (Box-folder 3-132)
    - Louis O'Shaughnessy, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 3-133)
    - J.J. Owens, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-134)
    - W. F. Pack, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-135)
    - J.R. Parrott, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 3-136)
    - E.R. Price, 1921 (Box-folder 3-137)
    - Harvey Lee Price, 1920 (Box-folder 3-138)
    - H.L. Price, 1921 (Box-folder 3-139)
    - W.R. Price, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 3-140)
    - Claude Pritchard, 1920 (Box-folder 3-141)
    - S.R. Pritchard, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-142)
    - S.R. Pritchard, 1921 (Box-folder 3-143)
    - Miscellaneous - R, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-144)
    - W.H. Rasche, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 3-145)
    - F.L. Robeson, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 3-146)
    - Miscellaneous - S, 1920 (Box-folder 3-147)
    - W.D. Saunders, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 3-148)
      - acquisition of land (timber/lumber)
      - VT farm, road building in Blacksburg
    - W.J. Schoene, State Entomologist (pest control), 1919-1921 (Box-folder 3-149)
    - W.L. Skaggs, 1921 (Box-folder 3-150)
    - John C. Skuse, 1921 (Box-folder 3-151)
    - E.A. Smyth, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 3-152)
    - H.S. Stahl, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 3-153)
    - S.B. Sutton, 1921 (Box-folder 3-154)
    - Miscellaneous - T, 1920 (Box-folder 3-155)
    - B.H. Van Oot, 1919-1921 (Box-folder 4-156)
    - R. A. Vivas, 1920 (Box-folder 4-157)
    - Miscellaneous - W, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 4-158)
    - Charles Wade, 1920 (Box-folder 4-159)
    - J.W. Watson, 1921 (Box-folder 4-160)
    - John E. Williams, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 4-161)
    - Col. F.E. Williford, Commandant, 1920 (Box-folder 4-162)
  - Subseries 2: Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1919-1922
    - A-D Correspondence, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 4-163)
      - Hazing
    - E-I Correspondence, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 4-164)
      - Square and Compass (Masonic Society and Secret Society)
    - J-M Correspondence, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 4-165)
      - Water supply
    - Johnson, T.C./Virginia Truck Exp. Station (Box-folder 4-166)
    - N-P Correspondence, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 4-167)
    - R-Z Correspondence, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 4-168)
      - letters - Norfolk & Western Railroad, letters from War Dept.
  - Subseries 3: Correspondence, 1921
    - A, 1921 (Box-folder 4-169)
      - Includes letter To Miss Ella G. Agnew re: forecast for the future of women students at VPI
      - Letter from Agnew remarking on the admittance of women at VPI for the first time in 'next September,' 1921
    - E.W. Allen, 1921 (Box-folder 4-170)
    - W.L. Andrews, 1921 (Box-folder 4-171)
    - B, 1921 (Box-folder 4-172)
      - Re: 1900 Bugle (only 4 copies and 2 sent to UVA
      - letter From attorney, re: murder case
      - Women students
    - W.E. Barlow, 1921 (Box-folder 4-173)
    - R.B.H. Begg, 1921 (Box-folder 4-174)
    - J. H. Bradford, 1921 (Box-folder 4-175)
    - F.L. Bruce, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 4-176)
    - W.A. Brumfield, 1921 (Box-folder 4-177)
    - O.C. Burkhart, 1921 (Box-folder 4-178)
    - Chas. G. Burr, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 4-179)
    - C, 1921 (Box-folder 4-180)
      - Lyric Theatre
      - Mr. Friel Cassel
      - A brief history of VPI, positions held by alumni
      - Women's Admittance
      - Letter and report from Virginia League of Women Votoers commending VPI on accepting women
    - Caldwell - Sites Co., 1921 (Box-folder 4-181)
    - Anna Campbell, 1921 (Box-folder 4-182)
    - Theo. B. Campbell, 1921 (Box-folder 4-183)
    - J.A.C. Chandler, 1921 (Box-folder 4-184)
    - W.B. Coggin, 1921 (Box-folder 4-185)
    - M. Cutherell, 1921 (Box-folder 4-186)
    - Miscellaneous - D, 1921 (Box-folder 4-187)
      - Women's Admittance
    - Mrs. M. M. Davis, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 4-188)
    - Westmoreland Davis, 1921 (Box-folder 4-189)
    - The Deans of VPI Colleges, 1921 (Box-folder 4-190)
    - K.C. Derring, 1921 (Box-folder 4-191)
    - Paul N. Derring, 1921 (Box-folder 4-192)
    - A.W. Drinkard, Sr., 1921 (Box-folder 4-193)
    - A.W. Drinkard, Jr., 1919-1921 (Box-folder 4-194)
    - James Duff, 1921 (Box-folder 4-195)
    - S.P. Duke, 1921 (Box-folder 4-196)
    - Wirt Dunlap, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 4-197)
    - Miscellaneous - E, 1921 (Box-folder 4-198)
    - W.T. Ellis - coal issues, 1921 (Box-folder 4-199)
    - [H.] Eoff, 1921 (Box-folder 4-200)
    - Miscellaneous - F, 1921 (Box-folder 4-201)
    - Faculty, 1921 (Box-folder 4-202)
    - Faculty Letters, 1921 (Box-folder 4-203)
    - J.G. Ferneyhough, 1921 (Box-folder 4-204)
    - J.B. Fogleman, 1921 (Box-folder 4-205)
    - F.D. Fromme, 1921 (Box-folder 4-206)
    - E.C. Gatewood, 1921 (Box-folder 4-207)
    - Carter Glass, 1921 (Box-folder 4-208)
    - H. Gudheim, 1921 (Box-folder 4-209)
    - Geo. W. Guy, 1921 (Box-folder 4-210)
    - Miscellaneous - H, 1921 (Box-folder 4-211)
    - Anna G. Hannas, 1921 (Box-folder 4-212)
    - D.L. Hatcher, 1921 (Box-folder 4-213)
    - H.H. Hill, 1921 (Box-folder 4-214)
    - Leroy Hodges, 1921 (Box-folder 4-215)
    - C.W. Holdaway, 1921 (Box-folder 4-216)
    - Holden, R.J, 1921 (Box-folder 4-217)
    - Hallie L. Hughes, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 4-218)
    - R.E. Hunt, 1921 (Box-folder 4-219)
    - J.R. Hutcheson, 1921 (Box-folder 4-220)
    - T.B. Hutcheson, 1921 (Box-folder 4-221)
    - Miscellaneous - I, 1921 (Box-folder 4-222)
    - Miscellaneous - J, 1921 (Box-folder 4-223)
    - B.O. James, 1921 (Box-folder 4-224)
    - J.L. Jarman, 1921 (Box-folder 4-225)
    - Jobbers Overall Co., 1921 (Box-folder 4-226)
    - Luther Johns, 1921 (Box-folder 4-227)
    - J.S.A. Johnson, 1921 (Box-folder 4-228)
    - T.C. Johnson, 1921 (Box-folder 4-229)
    - Eleanor T. Jones, 1921 (Box-folder 4-230)
    - M.C. Kibler, 1921 (Box-folder 4-231)
    - Fiske Kimball, Art Commission, 1921 (Box-folder 4-232)
    - Geo. W. Koiner - Agriculture, 1920-1922 (Box-folder 4-233)
    - R.V. Long, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 4-234)
    - Miscellaneous - M, 1921 (Box-folder 4-235)
    - Mrs. J.B. McBryde, 1921 (Box-folder 4-236)
    - J.P. McConnell, 1921 (Box-folder 4-237)
    - N.T. McManaway, 1921 (Box-folder 4-238)
    - W.H. Magee, 1921 (Box-folder 4-239)
    - Capt. A. Manonni, 1921 (Box-folder 5-240)
    - Chas. G. Maphis, 1921 (Box-folder 5-241)
    - J.H. Meek, 1921 (Box-folder 5-242)
    - Mrs. B.B. Munford, Co-op Education Association President - Rural Life, 1921 (Box-folder 5-243)
    - Miscellaneous - N, 1921 (Box-folder 5-244)
      - Women at VPI
    - E.W. Nichols, 1921 (Box-folder 5-245)
    - Miscellaneous - O, 1921 (Box-folder 5-246)
    - Chas. A. Osborne, 1921 (Box-folder 5-247)
    - Alvin Owsley, Am. Legion, 1921 (Box-folder 5-248)
    - Miscellaneous - P, 1921 (Box-folder 5-249)
    - Bruce R. Payne, 1921 (Box-folder 5-250)
    - R.G. Phelps, 1921 (Box-folder 5-251)
    - Pocahontas Coal Sales Co., 1921 (Box-folder 5-252)
    - L.T. Price, 1921 (Box-folder 5-253)
    - Lawrence Priddy, 1921 (Box-folder 5-254)
    - R.E. Priddy, 1921 (Box-folder 5-255)
    - W.M. Priddy, 1921 (Box-folder 5-256)
    - Miscellaneous - R, 1921 (Box-folder 5-257)
    - Miscellaneous - S, 1921 (Box-folder 5-258)
    - W.T. Sanger, 1921 (Box-folder 5-259)
    - B. Morgan Shepherd, 1921 (Box-folder 5-260)
    - J.P. Shultz, 1921 (Box-folder 5-261)
    - R.K. Spiller, 1921 (Box-folder 5-262)
    - Claude Swanson, 1921 (Box-folder 5-263)
    - Miscellaneous - T, 1921 (Box-folder 5-264)
    - Clement S. Ucker, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 5-265)
    - C.C Vaughan, 1921 (Box-folder 5-266)
    - Miscellaneous - W, 1921 (Box-folder 5-267)
    - Western Union, 1921 (Box-folder 5-268)
    - J. E. Williams, 1921 (Box-folder 5-269)
    - F.E. Williford, 1921 (Box-folder 5-270)
    - Wiley & Wilson, 1921 (Box-folder 5-271)
    - T. Gilbert Wood, 1921 (Box-folder 5-272)
    - James P. Woods, 1921 (Box-folder 5-273)
    - E.A. Wright Co., 1921 (Box-folder 5-274)
    - Miscellaneous - Y, Z, 1921 (Box-folder 5-275)
  - Subseries 4: Correspondence, 1922
    - Miscellaneous - A, 1922 (Box-folder 5-276)
    - R.B.H. Begg, 1922 (Box-folder 5-277)
    - W.M. Brodie, 1922 (Box-folder 5-278)
    - W.A. Brumfield, 1922 (Box-folder 5-279)
    - Miscellaneous - C, 1922 (Box-folder 5-280)
      - Moonshine
      - Virginia Historical Pageant
    - T.P. Campbell, 1922 (Box-folder 5-281)
    - W.G. Chrisman, 1922 (Box-folder 5-282)
    - Shreve Clark, 1922 (Box-folder 5-283)
    - M. Cutherell, 1922 (Box-folder 5-284)
    - Miscellaneous - D, 1922 (Box-folder 5-285)
    - H.A. Davies, 1922 (Box-folder 5-286)
    - The Deans, 1922 (Box-folder 5-287)
    - Paul N. Derring, 1922 (Box-folder 5-288)
    - A.W. Drinkard, 1922 (Box-folder 5-289)
    - W.T. Ellis, 1922 (Box-folder 5-290)
    - Houston Eoff, 1922 (Box-folder 5-291)
    - Miscellaneous - F, 1922 (Box-folder 5-292)
    - Faculty Blanket Letters, 1922 (Box-folder 5-293)
    - J.G. Ferneyhough, 1922 (Box-folder 5-294)
    - J.B. Fogleman, 1922 (Box-folder 5-295)
    - Miscellaneous - G, 1922 (Box-folder 5-296)
    - Carter Glass, 1922 (Box-folder 5-297)
    - H. Gudheim, 1922 (Box-folder 5-298)
    - George W. Guy, 1922 (Box-folder 5-299)
    - Miscellaneous - H, 1922 (Box-folder 5-300)
      - Coal line, coal supply
      - Henry Williams, Negro
    - M.C. Harrison, 1922 (Box-folder 5-301)
    - J.B. Haskell, 1922 (Box-folder 5-302)
    - H.H. Hill, 1922 (Box-folder 5-303)
    - Leroy Hodges, 1922 (Box-folder 5-301)
    - C.W. Holdaway, 1922 (Box-folder 5-305)
    - R.J. Holden, 1922 (Box-folder 5-306)
    - R.E. Hunt, 1922 (Box-folder 5-307)
    - J.R. Hutcheson - semi-centennial celebration, 1922 (Box-folder 5-308)
      - VPI Golden Jubilee
    - T.B. Hutcheson, 1922 (Box-folder 5-309)
    - Miscellaneous - J, 1922 (Box-folder 5-310)
    - J.S.A. Johnson, 1922 - 7/1/22 (Box-folder 5-311)
    - T.C. Johnson, 1922 (Box-folder 5-312)
    - Adam Leroy Jones, 1922 (Box-folder 5-313)
    - Eleanor I. Jones, 1922 (Box-folder 5-314)
    - Miscellaneous - K, 1922 (Box-folder 5-315)
    - T.W. Knote, 1922 (Box-folder 5-316)
    - G.W. Koiner, 1922 (Box-folder 5-317)
    - Miscellaneous - L, 1922 (Box-folder 5-318)
    - D.S. Lancaster, 1922 (Box-folder 5-319)
    - Claudius Lee, 1922 (Box-folder 5-320)
    - Miscellaneous - M, 1922 (Box-folder 5-321)
      - American Legion
      - Rev. Hared Sweet Tillinghast
    - A. Manonni, 1922 (Box-folder 5-322)
    - Chas. G. Maphis, 1922 (Box-folder 5-323)
    - J.P. McConnell, 1922 (Box-folder 5-324)
    - C.P. Miles, 1922 (Box-folder 5-3253)
    - Edw. C. Miller, 1922 (Box-folder 5-326)
    - Miscellaneous - N, 1922 (Box-folder 5-327)
      - National Student Commission for the Limitation of Armaments
    - C.M. Newman, 1922 (Box-folder 5-328)
    - Miscellaneous - O, 1922 (Box-folder 5-329)
    - J.J. Owens, 1922 (Box-folder 5-330)
    - Louis O'Shaughnessy, 1922 (Box-folder 5-331)
    - Miscellaneous - P, 1922 (Box-folder 5-332)
      - Declaration as an endorsements of our U.S. position relative to Soviet Union
      - National Civil Foundation
    - W.F. Pack, 1922 (Box-folder 5-333)
    - J.R. Parrott, 1922 (Box-folder 5-334)
    - E.R. Price, 1922 (Box-folder 5-335)
    - H.L. Price, 1922 (Box-folder 5-336)
    - J.G. Price, 1922 (Box-folder 5-337)
    - Lawrence T. Price, 1922 (Box-folder 5-338)
    - W.R. Price, 1922 (Box-folder 5-339)
    - W.M. Priddy, 1922 (Box-folder 5-340)
    - S.R. Pritchard, 1922 (Box-folder 5-341)
    - Miscellaneous - R, 1922 (Box-folder 5-342)
      - Betting at Football Games
    - W.H. Rasche, 1922 (Box-folder 5-343)
    - F.L. Robeson, 1922 (Box-folder 5-344)
    - R.I. Roop, 1922 (Box-folder 5-345)
    - E.L. Rowell, 1922 (Box-folder 5-346)
    - Miscellaneous - S, 1922 (Box-folder 6-347)
    - W.T. Sanger, 1922 (Box-folder 6-348)
    - W.D. Saunders - dairy farm, 1922 (Box-folder 6-349)
    - W.J. Schoene - crop pest commission, 1922 (Box-folder 6-350)
    - C.E. Seitz, 1922 (Box-folder 6-351)
    - W.L. Skaggs, 1922 (Box-folder 6-352)
    - E.A. Smyth, 1922 (Box-folder 6-353)
    - H.S. Stahl, 1922 (Box-folder 6-354)
    - J.W. Stull, 1922 (Box-folder 6-355)
    - Claude A. Swanson, 1922 (Box-folder 5-356)
    - Miscellaneous - T, 1922 (Box-folder 6-357)
    - J. Hop Taft, 1922 (Box-folder 6-358)
    - H.A. Thompson, 1922 (Box-folder 6-359)